Hello, everyone. I hope you have watched the last video where I introduced you to Isabelle's interface,
basic interface, and how to perform basic tasks in it.
So let me first recap what I did in the last video, and then I would start with this video.
So what did we do in the last video? What we did was
revise,
very good, let me just do that again, revise
basic functional programming concepts, and that included
carrying, which is annotation for writing down functions, and included also
lambda expressions, which is a way to write functions as well. And lastly,
what we did was
polymorphic datatype, polymorphic types, which is a way, which is very similar to
templates, for example, in object-oriented programming. So in this
story, and what we also did other than that was do an basic Isabelle interface introduction.
So what that meant, what that included was to, like, manipulating a theory file, and
writing down terms. This included numbers, and included lists, sets, products,
tuples, you can also call them tuples if you want, functions, and we also did
type annotations for all these terms.
Then we also showed the last thing, which was an important component, was
how to perform, or how to, not perform, but how to write down a logical specification,
and that was just introducing you to the logical connectives, and how do we
write theorems in Isabelle. So in this video, I mean, in the next few videos, the next main
topic that we will discuss is, the next topic that we will discuss in the next few videos, is
how to perform improves in Isabelle. So in this video, I will cover logical reasoning,
logical reasoning, both forward and backwards reasoning, and in the next video,
next, like, the other two types, the other two types of proofs that we will cover are also
proofs by substitution, and mathematical induction on natural numbers, right?